Guide to the Ruth Barcan Marcus Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Ruth Barcan Marcus papers
1937-2011
MS 1993
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
21.68
(58 boxes)
This collection comprises the papers of noted philosoper and Yale professor, Ruth Barcan Marcus. The papers primarily document Marcus' scholarly contributions to the field of philosophy, as well as her teaching career at Yale and other universities. The collection includes correspondence, subject files, notebooks, writings, teaching materials, audio recordings, and electronic files.
Marcus, Ruth Barcan
Scope and Contents
This collection comprises the papers of noted philosoper and Yale professor, Ruth Barcan Marcus. The papers primarily document Marcus' scholarly contributions to the field of philosophy, as well as her teaching career at Yale and other universities. The collection includes correspondence, subject files, notebooks, writings, teaching materials, audio recordings, and electronic files.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of the Ruth Barcan Marcus Trust, 2013.
Biographical / Historical
Ruth Barcan Marcus was a philosopher and a professor in the Yale University Philosophy Department, noted for her advances in the field of logic, as well as her outspoken advocacy for women in philosophy. Dr. Marcus was born Ruth Charlotte Barcan on August 2, 1921, and was raised in the Bronx, NY. She earned a bachelor's degree in mathematics and philosophy from New York University, as well as a master's degree and a doctorate in philosophy from Yale.
Dr. Marcus taught at Roosevelt University, the University of Illinois at Chicago, and at Northwestern University before joining the Yale faculty in 1973. She is noted for her advances in the quantification of modal logic and the theory of direct reference. She also wrote significant works on identity, essentialism, possibilia, belief, and moral conflict. She is perhaps most well-known for the development of the Barcan formula, an essential thesis of modal logic. After retiring from Yale in 1992, Dr. Marcus taught at the University of California, Irvine. She died at her home in New Haven on February 19, 2012.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials in Series V are open for research. Per our agreement with the donor materials in Series I, II, IV, VI, and VII are restricted until January 1, 2028; and materials in Series III are restricted until January 1, 2031.
Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
Arrangement
The papers are arranged into seven series: I. Correspondence, 1937-2011. II. Subject files, 1940-2011. III. Departmental files, 1973-2008. IV. Notebooks, 1947-1978. V. Teaching and course files, 1959-1995. VI. Writings, Speeches, and Lectures, 1942-2010. VII. Electronic files, circa 1980-2011.
Philosophers -- United States; Philosophy -- United States; Philosophy; Women philosophers -- United States; Women scholars -- United States; Marcus, Ruth Barcan; Yale University. Philosophy Department
- Correspondence, 1937-2011; Series I
  Scope and Contents
  This series consists of a substantial body of both incoming and outgoing correspondence, primarily between Ruth Barcan Marcus and colleagues at Yale University, as well as in the broader philosophy field. The correspondence primarily concerns Marcus' scholarship, writings, and professional service, issues and goings-on within philosophy and academia, as well as solicitations of feedback from colleagues about their own work. In particular, her correspondence both up-and-coming and established female colleagues reflects her championing of the work of women philosophers, as well as the mentorship she provided to those of a younger generation.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until January 1, 2028.
  - Chronological
    - 1947-1990 (Box 1, Folder 1-15)
    - 1991-2011, undated (Box 2, Folder 1-8)
  - Alphabetical
    - General
      - A, 1975-2000, undated (Box 2, Folder 9-10)
      - B-E, 1973-2010, undated (Box 3, Folder 1-8)
      - F-J, 1973-1999, undated (Box 4, Folder 1-7)
      - K-P, 1969-2003, undated (Box 5, Folder 1-6)
      - Q-Z, 1973-2010, undated (Box 6, Folder 1-10)
    - Individuals
      - Ackerman, D., 1981 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      - Adams, Marilyn McCord, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 2)
        General
        Correspondence regarding Kit Fine.
      - Adams, Robert M., 1995-1997 (Box 7, Folder 3-5)
      - Agassi, Joseph, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 6)
        Correspondence concerning Adolf Grünbaum.
      - Ahern, D., 1974 (Box 7, Folder 7)
      - al Habri, Azizah, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 8)
      - Albritton, Rogers, 1982, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 9-10)
      - Almog, Joseph, 1981-1992 (Box 7, Folder 11-13)
      - Altman, Sidney, 1985-1987 (Box 7, Folder 14)
      - Altrichter, Ferenc, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 15)
      - Anscombe, Elizabeth, 1969, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 16)
      - Anscombe, G. E. M., 1958 (Box 7, Folder 17)
      - Appiah, Anthony, 1976-1991, undated (Box 7, Folder 18-19)
      - Arrow, Kenneth, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 20)
      - Austin, J. L., Undated (Box 7, Folder 21)
      - Ayer, Alfred, 1978-1989 (Box 7, Folder 22-24)
      - Bacon, John, 1965-2000 (Box 7, Folder 25-28)
      - Baier, Annette, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 29)
      - Baier, Kurt, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 30)
      - Ballarin, Roberta, 1999, 2006 (Box 7, Folder 31)
      - Barry, Edward, 1993-1994 (Box 7, Folder 32)
      - Barton, Louis, 2004-2007 (Box 7, Folder 33)
      - Barwise, Jon, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 34)
      - Bearn, Gordon, 1983, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 35-36)
      - Becker, Larry, Undated (Box 7, Folder 37)
      - Belcher, Scott, 2005 (Box 7, Folder 38)
      - Belnap, Nuel, 1971, 2009 (Box 7, Folder 39-40)
      - Bennett, Karen, 2003-2004 (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - Bercovitch, Sacvan, 1980-1981, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 2-3)
      - Bergman, Merrie, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - Berk, Ed, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 5)
      - Bernstein, Richard, 1986-1987 (Box 8, Folder 6)
      - Berry, David, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 7)
      - Black, Max, 1989-1990 (Box 8, Folder 8)
      - Blumenfeld, D., 1973-1975 (Box 8, Folder 9)
      - Bobzien, Suzanne, 2004, 2006 (Box 8, Folder 10-11)
      - Boolos, George, 1987, 1996, undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
      - Brainard, Bill, Undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
      - Brand, Myles, 1974-1975 (Box 8, Folder 14)
      - Brandl, Johannes, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 15)
      - Braun, David, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 16)
      - Brittan, Gordon, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 17)
      - Brown, Charlotte, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 18)
      - Brown, Curtis, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 19)
      - Brueckner, Tony, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 20)
      - Burge, Tyler, 1979-1980 (Box 8, Folder 21)
      - Burnyeat, M. F., 1982, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 22)
      - Buss, Sarah, 1990, undated (Box 8, Folder 23)
      - Butler, Judith, 1995-1996 (Box 8, Folder 24)
      - Card, Claudia, 2009, undated (Box 8, Folder 25)
      - Carnielli, Walter, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 26)
      - Cartwright, Helen, 1976-1980, undated (Box 8, Folder 27)
      - Chalmers, David, 1996-1997, undated (Box 8, Folder 28-29)
      - Chappell, Vere, 1978, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 30-31)
      - Chellas, B. F., 1974-1975 (Box 8, Folder 32)
      - Chermak, C., 1982, undated (Box 8, Folder 33)
      - Chernoff, Fred, Undated (Box 8, Folder 34)
      - Chisholm, Roderick M., 1973 (Box 8, Folder 35)
      - Clark, R., 1973 (Box 8, Folder 36)
      - Coder, David A., 1978 (Box 8, Folder 37)
      - Cohen, Marshall, 1981-1982 (Box 8, Folder 38)
      - Cohen, Priscilla, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 39)
      - Cohen, Robert S., 1985 (Box 8, Folder 40)
      - Coleman, Jules, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 41)
      - Cometti, Jean-Pierre, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 42)
      - Cooper, John, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 43)
      - Copeland, B. J., 1985, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 44)
      - Costa, Horacio Arlo, 2005-2006 (Box 8, Folder 45)
      - Cresswell, Max, 1995, 1999 (Box 8, Folder 46)
      - Crews, Frederick, 1986, undated (Box 8, Folder 47)
      - Croddy, Steve, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 48)
      - Da Costa, Emilia, 1985, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 49)
      - Davidson, Donald, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 50)
      - Davidson, Lee, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 51)
      - Davis, Wayne, 1979-1980 (Box 8, Folder 52)
      - Deltete, Robert, 1983-1991 (Box 8, Folder 53-55)
      - Devitt, Michael, 2006 (Box 8, Folder 56)
      - Dickie, George, 2000, undated (Box 8, Folder 57)
      - Donagan, Barbara, 1991 August 16 (Box 8, Folder 58)
      - Dunn, Michael, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 59)
      - Engel, Joe, 2003 (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - Engel, Pascal, 1991-2001 (Box 9, Folder 2)
      - Engelen, Eva-Marie, 2000 (Box 9, Folder 3)
      - Ephron, Nora, 1996 September (Box 9, Folder 4)
      - Eveling, Kate and Stanley, 1996-2009 (Box 9, Folder 5)
      - Feferman, Solomon, 1976, 1986, 2005 (Box 9, Folder 6)
      - Feinberg, Joel, 1978-2002 (Box 9, Folder 7-10)
      - Fern, Richard, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 11)
      - Field, Hartry, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 12)
      - Fischer, John Martin, 1989, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 13)
      - Fish, Stanley, 2000-2002 (Box 9, Folder 14)
      - Fiss, Owen, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 15)
      - Fitch, Frederic, 1945-1973 (Box 9, Folder 16-21)
      - Fitch, Frederic and Alonzo Church (copies), 1937-1980 (Box 9, Folder 22)
      - Follesdal, Dagfinn, 1983-2006 (Box 9, Folder 23-25)
      - Foot, Philippa, 1981, undated (Box 9, Folder 26)
      - Forbes, Graeme, 2000, undated (Box 9, Folder 27)
      - Fox, Ivan, 1992-1995 (Box 9, Folder 28)
      - [Frank?], Gladys, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 29)
      - Frankfurt, Harry, 1982-1989 (Box 9, Folder 30-33)
      - Freeman, Eugene, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 34)
      - Friedman, Harvey and Michael, 1984-1994 (Box 9, Folder 35)
      - Fuchs, Alan, 1980-1981 (Box 9, Folder 36)
      - Garrett, Don, 1977, undated (Box 9, Folder 37)
      - Garson, James, 2007 (Box 9, Folder 38)
      - Geach, Peter, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 39)
      - Gemes, Ken, 1989-1992, undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
      - Gendler, Tamar, 1996 (Box 10, Folder 2)
      - Giamatti, A. Bartlett, 1980-1985, undated (Box 10, Folder 3-6)
      - Gianquinto, Marcus, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 7)
      - Giere, Ronald N., 1973 (Box 10, Folder 8)
      - Gochet, Paul, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 9)
      - Gorovitz, Samuel, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 10)
      - Gould, James A., 1971-1978 (Box 10, Folder 11)
      - Gray, Hannah Holborn, 1974-1977 (Box 10, Folder 12-13)
      - Greenspan, Patricia, 1975-1995 (Box 10, Folder 14)
      - Grewe, Rudolf, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 15)
      - Grill, Nicoletta, 1973-1975 (Box 10, Folder 16)
      - Grover, Dorothy, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 17)
      - Grünbaum, Adolf, 1979-2011, undated (Box 10, Folder 18-19)
      - Hacking, Ian, 1967, 1981, undated (Box 10, Folder 20-21)
      - Hall, Harrison, 1975-1976 (Box 10, Folder 22)
      - Hanna, Robert, 1988-1989 (Box 10, Folder 23)
      - Hanzel, Igor, 1996 (Box 10, Folder 24)
      - Harries, K., 1975 (Box 10, Folder 25)
      - Hartmann, Geoffrey, 1984, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 26)
      - Hertz, Neil, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 27-28)
      - Hill, Claire, 1996 (Box 10, Folder 29)
      - Hodges, Wilfred, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 30)
      - Hodgkin, A. G., 1983 (Box 10, Folder 31)
      - Hoekema, David, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 32)
      - Hoffman, Eric, 1997 (Box 10, Folder 33)
      - Holliday, Chris, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 34)
      - Hope, Kenneth, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 35)
      - Horty, John, 1994, 2001 (Box 10, Folder 36)
      - Hospers, John, The Monist, 1986-1987 (Box 10, Folder 37)
      - Hueber, Hilla, Philosophia, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 38)
      - Isay, Jane, 1974, undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
      - Jacob, Pierre, 1991-1993 (Box 11, Folder 2)
      - Jaeger, Robert, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 3)
      - Jansma, Mark, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 4)
      - Jubien, Michael, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 5)
      - Kaminer, Wendy, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 6)
      - Kaplan, Alice, 1993 December (Box 11, Folder 7)
      - Kaplan, David, 1973-1995, undated (Box 11, Folder 8-12)
      - Kazin, Alfred, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 13)
      - Kennedy, Donald, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 14)
      - Keupink, Alfons, 2008 (Box 11, Folder 15-16)
      - Khoury, Bernard, Educational Testing Service, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 17)
      - Körner, Stephan, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 18)
      - Korsgaard, Christine, 1986, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 19)
      - Kraut, Robert, 1994-1996 (Box 11, Folder 20)
      - Kripke, Saul, 1980, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 21)
      - Krois, Michael, 1993-1996 (Box 11, Folder 22)
      - Kuklick, Bruce, 2000-2001 (Box 11, Folder 23)
      - Kupperman, Joel, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 24)
      - Kyburg, Harry, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 25)
      - Ladd, John, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 26)
      - Lear, Jonathan, 1977-1980 (Box 11, Folder 27-28)
      - Lesser, Wendy, 2001 (Box 11, Folder 29)
      - Levi, Isaac, 1982-1992 (Box 11, Folder 30-31)
      - Levin, Richard, 1983-2001, undated (Box 11, Folder 32-33)
      - Levinson, Arnold, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 34)
      - Lewis, C. I., 1947-1960 (Box 11, Folder 35)
      - Li, Chenyang, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 36)
      - Lineback, Richard, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 37)
      - Linsky, Leonard, 1978, 1993 (Box 11, Folder 38-39)
      - Lucas, Billy Joe, 1989-1991 (Box 11, Folder 40)
      - MacIntyre, Alasdair, 2007 (Box 11, Folder 41-42)
      - Maddy, Penelope, 1996-2002 (Box 11, Folder 43-44)
      - Makarios, Selene, 2006 (Box 11, Folder 45)
      - Malcolm, Norman, 1947, 1973-1974, undated (Box 11, Folder 46)
      - Marti, Genoveva, 1994-2005 (Box 11, Folder 47)
      - Martin, Emily, 2009 (Box 11, Folder 48)
      - McConnell, Terrance, 1985-1987 (Box 11, Folder 49)
      - McKenzie, Ian, 1986-1988 (Box 11, Folder 50)
      - McMullin, Ernan, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 51)
      - Meisel, Martin, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 52)
      - Meyer, Michel, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 53)
      - Moberg, Dale, 1975, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 54)
      - Moore, Asher, 1958-1965, undated (Box 11, Folder 55)
      - Morano, Don, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 56)
      - Morgan, Doug, 1951-1954, undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
      - Mothersill, Mary, 1968-1992 (Box 12, Folder 2-5)
      - Murdoch, Iris, 1985-1988, undated (Box 12, Folder 6)
      - Nagel, Thomas, 1984 (Box 12, Folder 7)
      - Naumann, Barbara, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 8)
      - Neale, Stephen, 1990, 2010 (Box 12, Folder 9-10)
      - Nef, Frederic, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 11-12)
      - Nolan, Rita, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 13)
      - Nordhaus, William, 1987-1989 (Box 12, Folder 14)
      - Oliver, Alex, 1989, undated (Box 12, Folder 15)
      - Ott, Hugo, 1984 (Box 12, Folder 16)
      - Parsons, Charles, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 17)
      - Parsons, Terence, 1978, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 18-19)
      - Paul, Laurie, 1992-1993 (Box 12, Folder 20-21)
      - Pears, David, Undated (Box 12, Folder 22)
      - Peck, Ann, 1983 (Box 12, Folder 23)
      - Perry, John, Undated (Box 12, Folder 24)
      - Piper, Adrian, 1980-2002 (Box 12, Folder 25-26)
      - Pitcher, George, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 27)
      - Pojman, Louis, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 28)
      - Price, Connie C., 1976 (Box 12, Folder 29)
      - Pulbere, Simone, 2002 (Box 12, Folder 30)
      - Quine, Willard V., 1947-2006, undated (Box 12, Folder 31-35)
      - Rabb, T., 1977 (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - Railton, Peter, Undated (Box 13, Folder 2)
      - Read, Stephen, 1990-1992 (Box 13, Folder 3)
      - Reif, Rafael, 2009 (Box 13, Folder 4)
      - Remini, Robert, 1998 (Box 13, Folder 5)
      - Roberts, Lawrence, 1985-1986 (Box 13, Folder 6)
      - Ross, David, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 7)
      - Salmon, Nathan, 1979-1986 (Box 13, Folder 8-9)
      - Sanders, John, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 10)
      - Sauve, Kevin, 1994 (Box 13, Folder 11)
      - Schurz, Gerhard, 1999 (Box 13, Folder 12)
      - Searle, John, 1997 (Box 13, Folder 13)
      - Segerberger, Krister, 1996 (Box 13, Folder 14)
      - Sellars, Wilfred, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 15)
      - Sewell, W., 1979 (Box 13, Folder 16)
      - Sheehan, Thomas, 1988 (Box 13, Folder 17)
      - Shook, John, 2004 (Box 13, Folder 18-19)
      - Simon, Peter, 1992-1994 (Box 13, Folder 20)
      - Sinnott-Armstrong, Walter, 1998 (Box 13, Folder 21)
      - Skyrms, Brian, 1993-1997, undated (Box 13, Folder 22-23)
      - Slote, Michael, Undated (Box 13, Folder 24)
      - Smith, John E., 1976, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 25-26)
      - Smith, Quentin, 1993-1998 (Box 13, Folder 27-29)
      - Soames, Scott, 1982-1984, 1994 (Box 13, Folder 30)
      - Sorenson, Ralph, 1994 (Box 13, Folder 31)
      - Stalnaker, Robert, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 32)
      - Stevenson, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 33)
      - Strotz, Bob, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 34)
      - Stroud, Barry, 1983 (Box 13, Folder 35)
      - Suppes, Patrick, 1962, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 36)
      - Taft, Howard, 1973-1975 (Box 13, Folder 37)
      - Tharp, Leslie, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 38)
      - Thomson, Judith Jarves, 1979-2005, undated (Box 13, Folder 39-41)
      - Tierney, Hanne, 2005-2006 (Box 13, Folder 42)
      - Tobin, Jim, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 43)
      - Tomas, Vincent, 1967-1972 (Box 13, Folder 44)
      - Turner, Frank, 1988 (Box 13, Folder 45)
      - Ulam, S. M., 1979 (Box 13, Folder 46)
      - Vanderveken, Daniel, 1996 (Box 13, Folder 47)
      - Veatch, Henry, 1963-1972, undated (Box 13, Folder 48)
      - Vlastos, Gregory, 1986, 1990 (Box 13, Folder 49)
      - Wellek, René, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 50)
      - Wettstein, H., 1982, 1984, undated (Box 13, Folder 51)
      - Wiggins, David, 1974-1993, undated (Box 13, Folder 52-54)
      - Williams, Bernard, 1985, 2001 (Box 13, Folder 55)
      - Wolterstorff, Nicholas, 1988 (Box 13, Folder 56)
      - Woodfield, Andrew, 1986, undated (Box 13, Folder 57)
      - Yablos, Stephen, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 58)
      - Zalta, Edward, 1988 (Box 13, Folder 59)
      - Zemach, Eddy, 1984, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 60)
      - Zeman, J., Undated (Box 13, Folder 61)
      - Ziff, Paul, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 62)
- Subject files, 1940-2011; Series II
  This series consists of an assortment of files related to Ruth Barcan Marcus' research interests, scholarship, and professional service. A substantial number of the files concern the work of Marcus' colleagues in philosophy and other academic fields whose research and scholarship interested her. The series also includes a substantial body of biographical materials that Marcus compiled herself. These materials primarily document her professional accomplishments and employment history spanning the entirety of her career.
  - General, 1970-2007 (Box 14, Folder 1-5)
  - Abortion, 1982-1983 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences (AAAS)
    - General, 1977-1986 (Box 14, Folder 7-9)
    - Nominations, 1979-1984, undated (Box 14, Folder 10-11)
  - American Association of Philosophy Teachers (AAPT)
    - General, 1979 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Conference on Teaching Philosophy, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - American Council of Learned Societies, 1982-1983 (Box 14, Folder 14-15)
  - American Philosophical Association (APA)
    - General, 1975-1984, 2004-2006, undated (Box 14, Folder 16-24)
    - Board meeting, 1981-1982 (Box 14, Folder 25-26)
    - Budget, 1976-1981 (Box 15, Folder 1-2)
    - Committee members, 1980 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Committee on Lectures, Publication, and Research, 1981 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Constitution issues, 2003-2004 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Consultants, agenda proposal, end of term notice, 1977-1981 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - East Division, 1982-1983 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Graduate students letter, 1979 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Gruender funding request for Interamerican Conference, 1981 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Pacific Division, 1977-1981 (Box 15, Folder 10-11)
    - Sommers article, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Symposium, St. Louis, 1986 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Symposium honoring Ruth Marcus, 1991-1992 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Teaching newsletter, 1979 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Thank you note for gift, 1984 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Travel grants, 1980-1981 (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Western Division, 1978 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Anderson, Alan, 1973-1975 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Aristotle's syllogism, 1983, undated (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Arrow, Kenneth J., Undated (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Association for Symbolic Logic (ASL), 1976-1989 (Box 15, Folder 22-28)
  - Aristotelian Society, 1976 (Box 15, Folder 29)
  - Association for Women in Mathematics, 1987 (Box 15, Folder 30)
  - "The Background of Contemporary Philosophical Logic" (symposium), University of Miami, 1986-1987 (Box 15, Folder 31)
  - Bealer, George, "An Inconsistency in Direct Reference Theory", 2004 (Box 15, Folder 32)
  - Beck, L. W., "The Present State of the Profession of Philosophy", 1975 (Box 15, Folder 33)
  - Bellagio Study and Conference Center, 1973 (Box 15, Folder 34)
  - Bennett, Jonathan, "Thoughtful Brutes", Undated (Box 15, Folder 35)
  - Bercovitch, Sacvan, 1993 (Box 15, Folder 36)
  - Bickman, Stephen, 1979 (Box 15, Folder 37)
  - Bibliography
    - General, Undated (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Explanation, Undated (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Reference, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Bilkent University, 1997 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Biographical
    - General, 1946-2007 (Box 16, Folder 5-27)
    - Bibliography and vitae, 1983-1984 (Box 16, Folder 28)
    - Employment, 1959-1972 (Box 17, Folder 1-2)
    - "Intellectual Trajectories: Why People Study What They Do", at the Koerner Center, presentation by Ruth Marcus, Circa 2005 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Job offers, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 4-5)
    - List of papers by Marcus, with explanation of importance, Undated (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - New York University (NYU), citations from school publications, 1940-1941 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Professional service, 1947-1975 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Roosevelt University and Northwestern University salary documents, 1955-1963 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Yale job offer and negotiations, 1972-1973 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Undergraduate and graduate student records, 1941-1947 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Boer, Steven, 1980-1981 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Boston colloquium transcript, 1962 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Brewster, Kingman, records in Manuscripts and Archives, 2007 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Brewster, Kingman, Report of the President, 1976 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Broadie, Susan Waterlow, 1982-1991 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Brown University, 1979 (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Browning, Robert, 1974 (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Burgess, John, Quentin Smith, and Scott Soames, 1991-1997 (Box 17, Folder 19)
    Material relating to the dispute concerning Ruth Barcan Marcus' contributions to philosophy.
  - Calabresi, Guido, 1982-1986, undated (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - California Institute of Technology job offer, 1978 (Box 17, Folder 21-22)
  - Cambridge, Clare Hall, 1987-1990 (Box 17, Folder 23)
  - Cambridge Press, 1978 (Box 17, Folder 24)
  - Carr, David T., 1974 (Box 17, Folder 25)
  - Cartwright, Nancy, 1983-1993, undated (Box 17, Folder 26-28)
  - Cartwright, Richard, 1963, undated (Box 17, Folder 29-30)
  - Cassirer, Ernst, 1988-2000 (Box 17, Folder 31-32)
  - Catastrophe theory, 1977 (Box 17, Folder 33)
  - Causality, Undated (Box 17, Folder 34)
  - Celebrity, 1983 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences, 1976-1989 (Box 18, Folder 2-4)
  - Central Intelligence Agency (CIA), academic, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Century Club, 1983 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Chauviré, Christiane: Cerisy, 1994-1995 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Chicago Circle, 1967-1968, 1983 (Box 18, Folder 8-9)
  - China, 1984-1986, 1995 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Chomsky, Noam, 1986, 1992 (Box 18, Folder 11)